<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ResGro CompSysMed on ResGro CompSysMed</title>
    <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ResGro CompSysMed on ResGro CompSysMed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/phd01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/phd01/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;phd-student-position-65-e13-3-years-available-immediately&#34;&gt;PhD Student position (65% E13, 3 years) available immediately&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diseases are currently defined and diagnosed based on symptoms (e.g.,
hypertension, depression) or affected organs (e.g., heart failure,
nephropathy). Clearly, there is a lack of mechanistic understanding of diseases
that could improve disease definitions and allow for more informed selection
and development of therapies. To achieve such understanding we develop
integrative bioinformatics methods leveraging network analysis, machine
learning techniques, and statistical approaches. Your work will focus on the
development of graph-based machine learning techniques to identify disease- and
patient-specific dysregulated subnetworks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/tim_kacprowksi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/tim_kacprowksi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a research group leader at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics.  My
group works on network biology, multi omics integration and machine learning in
the context of systems medicine.  Previously, I spent some time in Odense,
Denmark, as a guest researcher at the Syddansk Universitet.  In my graduate
studies at the University of Greifswald, I analysed different omics data in the
context of common diseases. Before I joined the Interfaculty Institute of
Functional Genomics at the University Medicine Greifswald, I studied
bioinformatics in Saarbrücken, focussing on network biology. During my studies
I spent some time abroad at the University of Iceland. I was awarded a Honor&amp;rsquo;s
Degree in Bioinformatics from the Saarland University and the
Max-Planck-Institute for Informatics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/sepideh_sadegh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/sepideh_sadegh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD student in the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics at TU Munich. I
received my Bachelor’s degree in Biomedical Engineering from Amirkabir
University of Technology (Tehran, Iran) and my Master’s degree in
Bioinformatics from Saarland University (Saarbrücken, Germany). In my master
thesis I analyzed disease-specific gene regulatory networks in terms of
co-regulatory network motifs. My research interests include multi-omics data
and network biology. I am currently involved in REPO-TRIAL, a H2020 funded drug
repurposing project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/manuela_lautizi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/manuela_lautizi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a PhD student in the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics in collaboration
with the Institute of Pathology, both at TUM. I’ve originally joined Prof.
Baumbach’s lab to work on my master’s thesis in bioinformatics, focused to
identify pathway-based subnetwork of genes most significantly associated to
survival time of cancer patients. Other topics of my interest are machine
learning (both supervised and unsupervised), manipulation and analysis of the
data from a statistical point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/lorenzo_viola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/lorenzo_viola/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a master student in Engineering in Computer Science at Sapienza University,
Rome. My curriculum is focused on data mining and management, also on a large
scale. A bioinformatics course has inspired me to join the Chair of
Experimental Bioinformatics for developing my thesis project, dealing with
multimodal network-based epistasis detection on a genome-wide scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/niklas_probul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/niklas_probul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bachelor student in Bioinformatics at TUM and LMU in Munich and recently
joined the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics in Weihenstephan for my
bachelor thesis on the harmonisation of GWAS data for machine learning
purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/olga_lesina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/olga_lesina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I study bioinformatics since Oct‘2018 in Munich with a research interest in
human genetics and cancer biology. Before that I received a master’s degree in
biology at the LMU Munich. During my studies, I focused on molecular and cell
biology and protein biochemistry. I recently joined the Chair of Experimental
Bioinformatics as a Hiwi to work on the diseasome project for a better
understanding of a disease-gene interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/fanny_roessler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/fanny_roessler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a Bioinformatics Bachelor student at the Technical University of Munich and
the LMU since October 2016. I recently joined the Chair of Experimental
Bioinformatics at TUM as a HiWi to gain more practical experience in
bioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Student position (65% E13, 3 years) available immediately</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/phd01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/phd01/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diseases are currently defined and diagnosed based on symptoms (e.g.,
hypertension, depression) or affected organs (e.g., heart failure,
nephropathy). Clearly, there is a lack of mechanistic understanding of diseases
that could improve disease definitions and allow for more informed selection
and development of therapies. To achieve such understanding we develop
integrative bioinformatics methods leveraging network analysis, machine
learning techniques and statistical approaches. Your work will focus on the
development of graph-based machine learning techniques to identify disease- and
patient-specific dysregulated subnetworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-bring&#34;&gt;You bring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Degree in bioinformatics, molecular biology, computer science, or similar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid understanding of molecular biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with omics data analysis, graph analysis, machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong programming skills in Python, R, and / or Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Linux and HPC environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency in English in written and spoken language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong commitment and motivation, ability to work collaboratively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-offer&#34;&gt;We offer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics you will find a supportive and
productive research environment with a young, dynamic team of more than 20
international researchers at different stages in their career and education.
Furthermore, you will have the chance to participate in a large EU-wide project
and travel to international meetings with other scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send your application including your &lt;strong&gt;CV&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;grades&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;publications&lt;/strong&gt; (if any) and a
&lt;strong&gt;reference letter&lt;/strong&gt; to tim.kacprowski@wzw.tum.de.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De novo network enrichment</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/project/denovonetenrich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/project/denovonetenrich/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-info-coming-soon&#34;&gt;More info coming soon&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FeatureCloud</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/project/featurecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/project/featurecloud/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;more-info-coming-soon&#34;&gt;More info coming soon&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REPO-TRIAL</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/project/repo-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/project/repo-trial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
