<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ResGro CompSysMed on ResGro CompSysMed</title>
    <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ResGro CompSysMed on ResGro CompSysMed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/tim_kacprowksi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/tim_kacprowksi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a research group leader at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics.  My
group works on network biology, multi omics integration and machine learning in
the context of systems medicine.  Previously, I spent some time in Odense,
Denmark, as a guest researcher at the Syddansk Universitet.  In my graduate
studies at the University of Greifswald, I analysed different omics data in the
context of common diseases. Before I joined the Interfaculty Institute of
Functional Genomics at the University Medicine Greifswald, I studied
bioinformatics in Saarbrücken, focussing on network biology. During my studies
I spent some time abroad at the University of Iceland. I&amp;rsquo;ve been awarded a Honor&amp;rsquo;s
Degree in Bioinformatics from the Saarland University and the
Max-Planck-Institute for Informatics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/olga_tsoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 22:13:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/olga_tsoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will start in summer 2019 as a Postdoc at the Chair of Experimental
Bioinformatics. I graduated from Lomonosov Moscow State University and did PhD
in Kharkevich Institute in Moscow at professor Gelfand lab. There I studied the
evolution of transcriptional regulatory networks in bacteria. During my PhD I
shortly stayed at Stowers Institute for Medical Research, Kansas-City, where I
went on working on regulation of bacterial metabolic pathways. As a research
scientist, I worked in Skolkovo Institute of Science and Technology, Moscow on
3D chromatin structure analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/sepideh_sadegh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/sepideh_sadegh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a PhD student in the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics at TU Munich. I
received my Bachelor’s degree in Biomedical Engineering from Amirkabir
University of Technology (Tehran, Iran) and my Master’s degree in
Bioinformatics from Saarland University (Saarbrücken, Germany). In my master
thesis I analyzed disease-specific gene regulatory networks in terms of
co-regulatory network motifs. My research interests include multi-omics data
and network biology. I am currently involved in REPO-TRIAL, a H2020 funded drug
repurposing project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/manuela_lautizi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/manuela_lautizi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a PhD student in the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics in collaboration
with the Institute of Pathology, both at TUM. I’ve originally joined Prof.
Baumbach’s lab to work on my master’s thesis in bioinformatics, focused to
identify pathway-based subnetwork of genes most significantly associated to
survival time of cancer patients. Other topics of my interest are machine
learning (both supervised and unsupervised), manipulation and analysis of the
data from a statistical point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/amit_fenn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/amit_fenn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD candidate at the chair of Experimental Bioinformatics at TUM. My
project is the study of alternative splicing in heart and kidney using machine
learning to analyze multi-omics data. I studied cellular biology, specializing
in the mitochondria, during my Master&amp;rsquo;s at LMU. For my Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis, I
explored splicing within ribosomal protein genes, in the context of the
biogenesis of mitochondria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/weilong_li/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/weilong_li/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student in research unit of Epidemiology, Biostatistics &amp;amp;
Biodemography in University of Southern Denmark, and a member of the
Computational Biology group since October 2016. Currently, I am involved in
data analysis and software development for epigenome-wide association study. I
was master student majoring in applied mathematics at SDU, and did my master
thesis on GWAS simulation with twin design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/gihanna_galindez/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 22:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/gihanna_galindez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics at TU Munich. I
obtained my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Molecular Biology and Biotechnology from the
University of the Philippines. Then, I studied Life Science Informatics at
the University of Bonn in Germany. In my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis, I used machine
learning to identify chromatin features involved in immunity-related
transcriptional reprogramming in plants. I am working under the REPO-TRIAL
project to apply network analysis and machine learning for drug repurposing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/lorenzo_viola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/lorenzo_viola/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a master student in Engineering in Computer Science at Sapienza University,
Rome. My curriculum is focused on data mining and management, also on a large
scale. A bioinformatics course has inspired me to join the Chair of
Experimental Bioinformatics for developing my thesis project, dealing with
multimodal network-based epistasis detection on a genome-wide scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/chit_tong_lio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/chit_tong_lio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a biology master student from LMU Munich, where I have experiences in
working with sequencing data analysis. In my master thesis, I work at the Chair
of Experimental Bioinformatics on time course network enrichment analysis on
X-irradiated human fibroblast using TiCoNE and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/niklas_probul/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/niklas_probul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bachelor student in Bioinformatics at TUM and LMU in Munich and recently
joined the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics in Weihenstephan for my
bachelor thesis on the harmonisation of GWAS data for machine learning
purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/nils_mehrtens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/nils_mehrtens/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I study bioinformatics at TUM and LMU and recently joined the Chair of
Experimental Bioinformatics to research the relationship between miRNA
expression levels and various phenotype data in the context of my bachelor
thesis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/tim_faro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 22:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/tim_faro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in my third year of studies towards a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Bioinformatics
at the LMU and Technical University of Munich. Recently, I joined the Chair of
Experimental Bioinformatics in Weihenstephan for my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis on deep
learning for radiomics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/fanny_roessler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/fanny_roessler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a Bioinformatics Bachelor student at the Technical University of Munich and
the LMU since October 2016. I joined the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics
as a HiWi to gain more practical experience in bioinformatics. Since April 2019
I am working on my Bachelor thesis about time-series gene expression data
analysis of thyrotoxicosis using TiCoNE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/judith_bernett/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 12:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/judith_bernett/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Bioinformatics at the Technical University of Munich and the LMU since
October 2016. Recently, I joined the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics for
my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis on putative biomarkers for major cardiovascular events in
the SWISS-TAVI cohort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/christoph_kloppert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 12:18:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/team/christoph_kloppert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a bioinformatics bachelor student at the Technical University of Munich and
the LMU. I joined the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics for my bachelor’s
thesis on the cardiovascular outcome and timing of coronary angiography in high
risk groups.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
