<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Positions | ResGro CompSysMed</title>
    <link>/tags/positions/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/positions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Positions</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Positions</title>
      <link>/tags/positions/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Student position (65% E13, 3 years) available immediately</title>
      <link>/post/phd01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/phd01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diseases are currently defined and diagnosed based on symptoms (e.g.,
hypertension, depression) or affected organs (e.g., heart failure,
nephropathy). Clearly, there is a lack of mechanistic understanding of diseases
that could improve disease definitions and allow for more informed selection
and development of therapies. To achieve such understanding we develop
integrative bioinformatics methods leveraging network analysis, machine
learning techniques and statistical approaches. Your work will focus on the
development of graph-based machine learning techniques to identify disease- and
patient-specific dysregulated subnetworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-bring&#34;&gt;You bring&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Degree in bioinformatics, molecular biology, computer science, or similar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid understanding of molecular biology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience with omics data analysis, graph analysis, machine learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong programming skills in Python, R, and / or Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Familiarity with Linux and HPC environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency in English in written and spoken language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong commitment and motivation, ability to work collaboratively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-offer&#34;&gt;We offer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics you will find a supportive and
productive research environment with a young, dynamic team of more than 20
international researchers at different stages in their career and education.
Furthermore, you will have the chance to participate in a large EU-wide project
and travel to international meetings with other scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send your application including your &lt;strong&gt;CV&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;grades&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;publications&lt;/strong&gt; (if any) and a
&lt;strong&gt;reference letter&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tim.kacprowski@wzw.tum.de&#34;&gt;tim.kacprowski@wzw.tum.de&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
