<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ResGro CompSysMed</title>
    <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ResGro CompSysMed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.compsysmed.de/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at GQ2019</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/igld2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 13:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/igld2019/</guid>
      <description>Tim Kacprowski has been invited to give a talk at the Jahressymposium der Interdisziplinären Gruppe für Labor und Durchflussyztometrie, taking place from March 07-08 at the Congress Center in Frankfurt. The talk will be about &amp;ldquo;Zirkulierende miRNAs als potentielle Biomarker&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited talk at GQ2019</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/gq2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/gq2019/</guid>
      <description>Tim Kacprowski has been invited to give a talk at the 9th Gene Quantification Event qPCR dPCR &amp;amp; NGS 2019, taking place from March 18-22 at the TUM School of Life Sciences in Weihenstephan. The talk will be about &amp;ldquo;Circulating miRNAs as Potential Biomarkers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Student position (65% E13, 3 years) available immediately</title>
      <link>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/phd01/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.compsysmed.de/post/phd01/</guid>
      <description>Project description Diseases are currently defined and diagnosed based on symptoms (e.g., hypertension, depression) or affected organs (e.g., heart failure, nephropathy). Clearly, there is a lack of mechanistic understanding of diseases that could improve disease definitions and allow for more informed selection and development of therapies. To achieve such understanding we develop integrative bioinformatics methods leveraging network analysis, machine learning techniques and statistical approaches. Your work will focus on the development of graph-based machine learning techniques to identify disease- and patient-specific dysregulated subnetworks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>